CHIZARAM CHINEDU

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

https://github.com/chizaram92 chizwil@gmail.com (214)-417-3066

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Passionate front-end developer with 5+ years of experience using JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for client-facing landing pages. Specializes in using Reactjs framework to build Single-Page Applications.

SKILLS

UI Web Technologies: HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Javascript(ES6+), React.js, jQuery, Materialize,

GSAP, Wordpress, Bootstrap

BACK-END: Mongo Db, PostgreSQL

LANGUAGES: Python, Javascript, PHP, HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3

TOOLS: GIT, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Indesign, Adobe Photoshop, Bit Bucket, Postman

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RD3STUDIOS, Houston, TX — Front-End Engineer

FEB 2019 - PRESENT

- Collaborating with a team that includes a UI/UX developer and a brand strategist using Figma for mockups and sketches and Slack for communicating.
- Converting static websites to dynamic websites.
- Validating completed sites including debugging and testing.
- Responsible for quality assurance of completed websites, including validating web forms, links and image tags.

VECCHIA GLOBAL SERVICE, Houston, Tx — Web Developer (part-time)

AUG 2019 - NOV 2019

- Collaborated with the client to develop a clear project vision and business goals.
- Designed and implemented companies websites from mockup to development using HTML,
 CSS and jquery.
- Applied SEO best practices to keep client's websites on Google's first page.
- Designed all brand identities including logos, color scheme and business cards.

TRYBLE, Lagos, Nigeria — FullStack Developer

MAY 2018 - NOV 2018

- Developed the CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) features in the web application.
- Developed front end using HTML, CSS, Reactis.
- Built Restful API and OAuth using Nodejs, Expressjs, Passportjs.
- Extensively used GIT for version control and regularly pushed the code to GitHub
- Implemented MVC web framework in the core design of the web application.

Freelance Web Developer/Designer

FEB 2016 - MAR 2018

- Worked with 8+ organizations from around the world, developing websites that include e-commerce, landing pages and single-page applications.
- Increased traffic and enhanced page ranking by improving website structure, performing Search Engine Optimization (SEO) and Search Engine Marketing (SEM) for local improvements.
- Developed UI/UX strategies that include wireframes and mockups and for small and local enterprises.
- Edited HTML/CSS/JavaScript and plugins via WordPress.

PROJECTS

GOODREVIEW: A book review blog. **Link:** https://bit.ly/2vmUukW

Skills used: React, MongoDB, Nodejs, Expressjs

HILLTOPTIRES: A landing page for a local tire shop.

Link: https://bit.ly/39hjOHB **Skills used**: HTML, CSS, Materialize

Portfolio Website: A website that showcases my work and about me.

Link: https://bit.ly/2wnsZHL

Skills used: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Materialize

EDUCATION

LEARNINGFIELD SCHOOL, Lagos, Nigeria - High School Diploma

UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON, Houston, Tx - B.S Computer Science.

Completed 3 years towards a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Relevant Coursework: Programming & Data Structure, Intro to Automata & Computability, Linear Algebra, Statistics for Sciences, Computer Org & Architecture.

ONLINE EDUCATION

CODECADEMY: Web Development Career Path

UDACITY: Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree